Previously on Smallville...
I've picked out a nice little
font for my exposé.
I actually had another
headline in mind.
"The Blur murders Lois Lane."
Ugh!
Ugh! No!
I know you're out there somewhere!
I've been keeping an eye on you.
I have to see you.
How do you feel about phone booths?
Hello?
This is the Red-Blue Blur.
I received your letter.
What I've really
been wondering is...
What is it that you need?
I need your help.
But you can't tell anyone about it.
I promise.
I wouldn't ask, Lois,
if it weren't a matter
of life or death.
Welcome to Checkmate.
We've been blocked by a new player.
How do you get yourself
into these things, Lane?
Good to see you. Hey.
The guy's inside, boss.
Says he'll only show it to you.
Wants to collect the
million-dollar reward.
Really.
Ladies.
Hey, dollface.
Ah, my old friend.
It's been too long.
Hey.
Glad to have you back, Ray.
Good to be back, darling.
Well...
As your ex-district attorney...
I'd like to thank you all for
joining me in celebrating
the national treasure
that is our American
justice system.
You know...
they kicked me out of office...
they charged me with
attempted murder...
They even tried to
put me away for life,
and yet...
here I am.
So...
I understand you have
something for me.
What about my million dollars?
Don't test me, son.
Lois!
Clark?
I told you to find the story.
Not be the story.
One of you want to
tell me what happened?
Let me guess.
You two have a lovers' spat?
Clark and I don't spat.
There was no spatting.
What Lois is saying is that we try
not to let our personal lives
get in the way of our jobs.
Well, you don't have
to "try" anymore.
Because you're both fired.
♪  Smallville 9x17 ♪
Upgrade
Original Air Date on April 23, 2010
♪ Somebody save me ♪
♪  "Save Me" performed by Remy Zero ♪
♪ let your warm hands
break right through ♪
♪ somebody save me ♪
♪ I don't care how you do it ♪
♪ just stay ♪
♪ stay ♪
♪ come on ♪
♪ I've been waiting for you ♪
♪ just stay with me ♪
♪ I've made this whole
world shine for you ♪
♪ just stay ♪
♪ stay ♪
♪ come on ♪
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --
Chloe.
Can you believe it? I'm early.
No, Lois, "early"
is when you arrive
at your destination by a set time,
not when you can see it
from seven blocks away.
Unh-unh, nobody's raining
on this girl's parade today.
Clark's taking me up
to the roof tonight
to do a little stargazing.
O-Kay.
That explains the 911
to the craigslist queen.
Long live the queen.
I can't believe you
got one so fast.
I kind of noticed that Clark
has this thing for telescopes.
Do you think he'll like it?
But what is it exactly
about a telescope
that merits 76 trombones
and big parade?
Well...
Tonight's the night.
In the words of the general...
it's time to drop
the L-bomb. What?!
You mean to tell me that you guys
haven' volleyed the word yet?
Among other significant
relationship milestones.
I don't know -- things used
to be easier with Clark,
you know, back in the
days when you'd wake up
and the first thing
you'd do is check
for a text or an e-mail,
and it'd be there, waiting for you?
Anyway, things have
been different...
Ever since we decided
we could keep secrets
from each other.
But that's all changing tonight.
Wait a minute. Secrets?
Uh, changing how?
No more secrets.
It's time to take our
baggage out of the closet.
I mean, if we "L" each other,
then..
nothing should come between us,
right?
Hey! Do you ever
check your voicemail?
Looks like somebody missed
breakfast in bed with
Oliver this morning.
I'm not here to talk about my love life.
That makes two of us.
I'm here to talk about yours. Whoa.
Can't we just stick to a topic
like aliens assimilating the earth?
This isn't about
assimilating, Clark.
Zod has powers now,
and you told him all
of your secrets.
This is not a good time
to bring Lois in, too.
Lois? Yeah.
She told me about
your big date tonight
where you both are gonna
come clean with everything.
I'm not gonna tell Lois anything.
I'm making Lois dinner tonight
so she shares her secret.
She's been keeping
something from me.
I didn't want to use my
abilities to spy on her.
It's been driving me crazy.
So you're gonna
seduce it out of her?
Clark, you're the
reason all of this
is happening to begin with.
I have not called her
as The Blur in months.
That doesn't matter, Clark.
The second that your
back-in-black alter ego
asked Lois to lie about the Blur
was the day that you asked her
to lie to the person
that she loves,
which is you.
And she did.
A relationship with
secrets can never work.
Look at you and Oliver.
Everything's out in the open.
That is because we both
understand that our relationship
comes second to a higher calling.
Clark, you and Lois --
don't have to be any different.
Now, if Lois is gonna
trust me tonight,
maybe it's time I trusted her.
Hey.
Did you, uh, get my message?
Yep.
So, we're still on for tonight?
Definitely.
What's in the box?
A surprise.
It's gonna be a long day.
Yep.
How about a sneak preview?
Sometimes, I swear you
have more than two hands.
Either that kiss altered
my sense of time and space
or this place is busier than usual.
It's a big news day.
I think it has something
to do with our new editor.
Another editor?
They should just install
a rotating door up there.
Obviously, our illustrious owner
has just spun some big
wheel of fortune in the sky
to see who'd be steering
the ship this week.
Well...
I guess I pulled the
lucky number this week.
Franklin Stern.
You must be the lovely and
charming miss Lane, I presume.
Uh, miss Lane is an acquired taste.
I-it's just that ever
since Tess went away,
we've gone through
a lot of editors.
Well, not for long.
The board just launched
a global search
for the next editor-in-chief.
And I intend to make
their decision very easy.
And you decided to
start your campaign
by downsizing the desk inventory?
Miss Lane...
...I've been, uh, reading
through the personnel files
to identify any red flags,
and I understand you two
are entangled in an
interoffice relationship.
No. No, sir.
Yeah. Right.
Well, for whatever reason,
it seems you're both spending
so much time out of the office
trying to reel in the big fish,
you're not delivering
the daily catch.
To be fair, sir,
we've both turned in
some pretty big stories.
Here's a bigger one --
our fair city's disgraced D.
A., Ray Sacks,
just had is life sentence reversed.
He gets out o prison today.
Only one of these stays on the desk
at the end of the day.
May the best reporter win.
Oliver gave you keys to his office.
He must trust you with just
about all of his secrets.
Tess.
I thought you were
supposed to be underground.
You know, if you're
having a hard time
finding your way there,
I'm sure I could help.
So we're over the temporary truce
and straight back to "
fire at will."
Okay.
Just remember, Chloe,
that out there,
I might be M.I.A., but in here...
I'm still C.E.O.
Where is Oliver?
Out of town.
I was curious how you two...
got into each other's orbit.
Mutual friends,
which I understand you could
use some help finding,
considering the fact that you
have to go to outer space
to look for them.
The Kandorians?
You'll see, Chloe, they're
better as allies than enemies.
Clark gets that.
Why don't you and Oliver?
Clark optimistically thinks
that Zod will be happy wearing
an apron and slinging coffees.
We don't...
Especially now that he has powers.
"We"?
As in, you and Green Arrow?
Chloe...
I get what you see in your heroes,
but what do they see in you?
I could ask Zod the
same question about you,
but I guess I don't
have to anymore.
I've been watching you two,
and it seems like Zod
hasn't been home for
dinner for quite a while.
Be careful, miss Mercer.
At this rate, you're gonna
run out of people to betray.
I don't know what's worse, Clark --
that they freed the D.A.
that threw me off the roof
or that our editor
threw us in the ring
to wrestle for the same desk.
Don't worry --
if we land a big enough story,
we can save both our jobs.
Now, in order for him
to reverse his sentence,
Sacks must still have powerful
friends down at City Hall.
And according to the
underground blogs,
he's having a "welcome home"
party tonight at Maxwell's.
Crime kingpins like to
keep out the outsiders.
It'd be easier to
crash the White House
than it would be to
sneak into that party.
Look, we only have till the end
of the day to get this done.
I think we'd cover more
ground I we split the work.
That's a good idea.
Can't wait for tonight.
Hey, it's me -- Lois.
Guess you're out.
It's strange to think that I can
leave a message for The Blur.
I mean, well, not strange/weird --
it's just -- you know what I mean.
It's hard to picture The
Blur screening his calls --
not that you'd be screening my
calls or anything, but I d--
Me again. Got cut off.
You know, that's not lot of time
for someone to leave a message.
That beep comes at you pretty fast.
Then again, you are The Blur,
of course.
I'm sure you'd like it fast,
but I just --
Here's the deal.
I'm on a story about
our deadly ex-D.A.
Now, normally, I'd be working
with my partner in reporting,
but I want to keep
him safe, secure,
and as far away from Sacks and
his murderous mob as I can.
Clark's not bulletproof,
but you are.
Be my wingman?
Lois will find a way to see Sacks
before the party tonight.
Chloe, I have to find him first.
Look, I get it, Clark.
I'm spending a small
fortune of Oliver's money
to update the security
system here at Watchtower.
Plus I have a satellite
trained on your
fortress at all times
now that Zod knows your zip code.
I understand the instinct
to protect the ones that you love.
You know, half of being in
a relationship with Lois
is protecting her from herself.
Actually, she's not the only one
Sacks is gunning for right now.
According to the Internet,
he's offering a
million-dollar reward
for anyone who can supply him
with an image of The Blur.
Again? What's with this guy and
his obsession with The Blur?
Maybe it has something
to do with the fact
you publicly disgraced him
and threw him in prison.
Since he's been out,
I have a hard time tracking him down.
Well, Sacks is all about the V.
I.P. treatment.
Maybe he's got a favorite
bar or restaurant.
Someplace that he
would want to go to
after being locked
down for eight months.
Ah.
Our paroled prosecutor does
have a favorite haunt,
but it isn't exactly five-star.
Mr. Sacks, Lois Lane from
The Daily Planet.
You may remember me from the
roof of The Daily Planet.
Oh, yes. Yes, I remember you.
You have a nasty habit
of always landing on your feet,
don't you, Lane?
And now I need to land a story.
So, who let you out of your cage?
Since I'm the one that
you sent skydiving
without a parachute,
I figure I'm at least owed a quote.
You have too much faith
in The Blur, Lane,
to think you can meet
with me like this alone.
My editor knows where I am.
Hurt me, and you'll
be back behind bars
before this pizza cools off.
Oh, I won't hurt you, no. He will.
And this time,
they won't find me guilty
because they'll never
find your body.
It's him! Come on! Go! Go!
Wait!
Thank you...
for saving my bacon.
I'd be two strips of
pain on the pavement
if you hadn't gotten my call.
What call?
You have no idea what it means
that you trusted me enough
to let me help you
these past weeks.
I have never felt such a sense
of purpose in my entire life.
Whatever you need...
you can count on me.
Payday.
T-that million's mine.
I g-- I got a picture of The Blur!
What you've got is two choices --
you either trash that photo,
or I throw you in he trash!
Ugh!
Lois, stop!
Who are you calling?
It's not important, Clark.
No, that's The Blur, isn't it?
Why would you think that?
And what are you even doing here?
Lois, you told me that you
stopped talking to The Blur.
All those secrets that you've
been keeping from me --
it's him, isn't it?
Okay, this is between
The Blur and me.
That's all I can tell you.
Lois, do you even know who
you're really talking to?
Okay, what's going on here?
Clark, you don't
need to be jealous.
No, I'm not. I just --
Lois, I need to know who that is.
You did not just ask me that.
Is this about the story?
You want me to give up The
Blur just to save our job?
Lois, I'm trying
to save you.
Don't -- don't you think that,
sometimes,
you might have a little
too much blind faith?
Why? Because if he trusted me,
he'd show himself? Is that it?
Lois.
Okay, I need you to listen to me.
No, Clark...
I am sure he is dyin tell me,
but how could anyone
who cares about me
put me in that kind of position?
I-if I knew his true identity,
then every lowlife with
high hopes of hurting him
would come after me,
and he would never put
me in that kind of danger
just to get a secret off his back.
That's why I trust him.
I take it your search for
Sacks didn't go so well.
I found Sacks,
but I may have lost Lois,
or at least her trust.
Oh, no.
I know that look. What happened?
I did this to myself, Chloe.
I asked Lois to keep her
calls with The Blur a secret,
and she did...
even from me
and now someone else is calling
her pretending to be The Blur.
Why? Who would want to
Blur a mile your shoes?
I don't know -- Checkmate,
Zod, Tess.
They've all been
circling my secret.
I stole her phone to see
who she was calling.
She's already deleted the list.
You know, as much as I don't want to,
I have to say...
it's pretty impressive
how committed Lois is
to protecting The Blur.
From me.
Yeah, talk about a
Kafkaesque nightmare.
I almost ended it all
and told her everything
till she reminded me why I can never
put her in that kind of danger.
Look, I need to find whosever
lying to Lois using my identity.
She said she had
something to tell him.
And you want Watchtower
to trace the call.
Got it.
I would have called you on my cell,
but I can't find it.
Listen, someone photographed
you on their phone,
and they're about to
sell it to Ray Sacks.
I don't know when you'll get this,
so I'll blitz his bash at Maxwell's
and try to run interference,
but you need to get
there as soon you can.
Piece of cake.
... with attempted murder.
They even tried to
put me away for life,
and yet...
here I am.
So, uh...
I understand you have
something for me.
What about my million dollars?
Don't test me, son.
Lois!
Clark?
Oops.
Sorry about your million dollars.
Oh, that's okay, kid.
We don't need that picture.
We just need you.
Three years of selfless
service to this paper,
and the new editor on the
block just up and fires me.
Well, not just you, Lois.
Well, at least one of us
would have kept their job
if you hadn't been so obsessed
with unmasking The Blur.
I don't know how you found
out about that photo,
but crashing Sacks' party?
Just how many hurdles
are you willing to jump
to expose the person that
I'm trying to protect?
You jumped out of a cake,
Lois, and you slugged me.
It was just a distraction.
I had to do something extreme
to destroy that extremely
dangerous picture,
no thanks to you.
Lois. No, save it.
I don't know why you suddenly
have it in for The Blur,
but whatever you're
gonna tell me right now
isn't gonna make a difference.
I'm seeing a whole other
side of you, Clark,
and for the first time...
I'm not a fan of the view.
I take it this is the official
invitation to join you --
the black king.
Your work on this operation
has proven to be
surprisingly invaluable.
They have all witnessed The Blur.
Pieces of his identity
have been locked
within their minds.
They simply need to be severed.
And you're extracting
their memories
with this whole "Jedi
mind control" thing.
Very impressive
interrogation skills.
Listen, Mr. Lord,
I am no friend of The Blur,
but why are you after him?
You are aware, Sacks, that...
Metahumans exist on the planet.
I assume this Checkmate agency
wants to use them to
protect and serve?
That's the white queen's plan.
Waller barks orders
from behind a desk.
I work in the real world,
a world that needs the rule of law.
Anything outside the
natural order is...
unpredictable.
Now, correct me if I'm wrong --
you have powers...
You're one of them.
Which is exactly why I know
how dangerous they can be
and why I plan...
on eliminating them.
Chloe, when did you find this?
Can't you get a clearer picture?
Whoa, Clark, okay, one at a time.
I was following Lois
just in case she found
Sacks before you did,
and I got the security footage
from a camera 60 floors up.
Now, unfortunately, zoom technology
isn't exactly on par
with X-ray vision.
Where was Lois taken?
I don't know.
I lost the car right after
it went into Rombauer Tunnel.
This has to be Sacks.
I did some digging.
Right around the time that
our devious D.A. walked,
all his new little prison friends
who were sent up the river
were transferred off the grid.
Chloe, I know these guys.
I put every one of
them behind bars.
They're all violent offenders,
and the only person who can
authorize their transfer
is the Governor
who did you say
threw Sacks' little
"welcome home" mobster ball?
Some tycoon named Maxwell Lord.
Three guesses who the
largest contributor
to the governor's
re-election fund was.
With that kind of influence,
Lord has some serious
strings he can pull.
If Maxwell Lord wants The Blur,
that's exactly who he'll get.
You should see Lord's
setup downstairs.
This guy is a major player,
and he has just given me...
the key to the city.
Checkmate.
You're fighting it.
You know him, don't you?
Get away from her!
Ah.
I see we're past
formal introductions.
Stop.
One wrong step...
and I'll eviscerate every
last thought in her head.
You're using their memories
to learn my identity.
Let them go.
They don't know who I am.
True.
They've only seen glimpses
of your face -- nothing more.
You've been careful.
Except for this one.
Even unconscious...
her mind protects memories of you.
Maybe she doesn't have any.
Or maybe the connection
between you two...
is stronger.
Stronger than the fear that
binds you with the others,
stronger...
because of love.
You're here.
I-I can't know who you are.
I'd give anything
to see your face...
... to know your name.
But you can't protect us
if we know who you are.
I understand that now.
Go.
Sorry, Max. Little
change of itinerary.
So it's true --
the red queen does exist.
I guess the upside to unemployment
is you on't have to pick
out a tie every morning.
You're beating yourself up,
aren't you?
Oh, which "me"?
The Blur that Lois
would die to protect
or the boyfriend that Lois
is protecting him from?
Don't be so hard
on yourself, Clark.
Not everyone with a press pass
is also moonlighting as the
city's greatest superhero.
And the whole
phone/rooftop/blur thing --
at least give yourself
creative points
for trying to be as honest
as you could with Lois.
I guess if half of
me has Lois' trust
and the other half
gets the rest of her,
it all works out in some weird way.
There's only one
problem with that --
one of those halves
has to say goodbye.
I finished tracing the
number of our rogue blur...
to R.A.O. Industries.
It was Zod.
Everything he said
about brotherhood,
it was all a lie.
Of course he's the one
who's been using Lois.
I know you want to go and take
your anger out on Zod right now,
but you and I both know
that there's something
you have to take care of first.
Until you can tell Lois
that you are the one and only Blur,
anyone with a voice
modulator and a calling plan
can pretend to be you.
I know what I have to do.
Hello?
Lois, thank you for coming.
Well, when The Blur leaves
a handwritten message,
you better believe I'm there.
Chalk it up to the curiosity
of a recently
unemployed reporter...
but since we've been
doing this cell to cell,
why are we back to
doing this old-school?
I wanted to have this conversation
in a place that meant
something to both of us.
Wow. Sounds awfully official.
But, hey you're the boss.
So, what's my next
impossible mission?
There won't be one, Lois.
I'm sorry. This is our
last conversation.
Last conversation
today or for a while?
If you have to go back on
another hiatus, I understand.
I'll be there.
As in, our last talk...
Forever.
No.
Our relationship put you at risk.
I know that we would do
anything to protect each other.
What if, one day, I'm too late?
But you don't understand.
I don't care about the risk.
When I'm working with you,
I'm doing something good,
something right.
You don't need me for that.
But I do need you,
and maybe I didn't realize
it until it was too late,
but this the most
important part of my life.
Well, there must be...
some other part that
means more to you.
When I'm with you,
it's about more than what I want,
who I want.
It is something that
is bigger than me.
I wish things could
be different, Lois.
This is the only way
I can protect you.
I won't call again.
If anyone calls
claiming to -- to be me,
don't believe them.
No matter what they
say or what happens,
you can't trust them
no, please.
I will be watching over you.
I promise.
Goodbye, Lois.
Goodbye.
I'm glad you still came up
after what we talked
about on the street.
It's beautiful, Clark.
Thank you.
What is it, Lois?
You know you can tell me anything.
Can I?
Then, why did I lie to you?
We both agreed we would keep
some things to ourselves.
I've been talking
to The Blur, Clark.
Doing things for him,
sharing things with him that
I couldn't share with you.
It's probably just the
reporter blood in you, right?
It was more than that.
But we...
I talked to him, and it's over.
He doesn't want me
in his life anymore.
Well, there's someone standing
right here who still does.
It's okay.
You don't have to be
okay with it, Clark.
It's not right for me to
ask that of you, Clark.
He meant a lot to you, didn't he?
It's not like this with you.
I wish you could understand
what it felt like to have this...
A calling...
A duty to people in -
in the world.
It..
Made my feelings for you
and everything else seem...
selfish,
like there's a whole world
out there that needs you,
but if you take anything
from it for yourself,
it's at someone else's expense.
Lois, I do understand.
How?
I guess, with him gone,
the question is...
am i enough?
-- Sync, corrected by elderman --
-- for www.addic7ed.Com --